Ryan Bowler

+61466027037 github.com/ryanbprog ryanbprog.com linkedin.com/in/ryan

A passionate and professional problem solver with 10+ years in engineering, driven by a hunger for learning and a deep love for building things. Whether it's crafting a sleek front-end or diving into the nitty-gritty of the back-end, I love what I do and I thrive on problem solving.

Projects

My Portfolio (Astro, Typescript, Tailwind) - View Repo

Provides an in-depth look at my projects, professional experience, and personal background

Dev Trainer (Typescript, React, Next.js, Express, MongoDB (Mongoose), Redis, Tailwind, OAuth2.0, Gemini) - View Repo

An app that acts as a reference and learning aid to developers. It allows you to create lists of things like shortcuts or generate code snippets with Al that you frequently need but often forget.

Better Spanish (Typescript, React, Next.js, Express, PostgreSQL (Drizzle), Tailwind) - View Repo

A Spanish language learning app design to speed up fluency with a focus on high frequency words.

Dymone (Typescript, React, Next.js, Sanity, Stripe, Tailwind) - <u>View Repo</u>

A e-commerce site for a luxury jewellery online retailer, intergrated with Sanity as the CMS and stripe to process payments and manage products

Work Experience

Bruce Rock Engineering - April 2022 to Jan 2023

- Implemented new engineering design procedures to improve communication and quality of the final product
- Programmed and managed a suite of tools that automated a range of repetitive engineering design tasks
- Managing the engineering drawing processes as a whole

Mettler-Toledo - August 2020 to Jan 2022

- · Maintaining and developing new and existing mechanical designs with the use of specialised 3D software
- Managed and evolved an assigned product range as an SME, providing technical guidance and driving design improvements
- · Reviewing and auditing others work to maintain a high design standard across the department

KMG - June 2020 to August 2020

Mettler-Toledo - October 2019 to April 2020

(Please visit my LinkedIn to view full career history)

Education

Equinium College

IT (Backend Development)

UniCourse Limited

Engineering (Manufacture)

Meta

Frontend Development Certification

Advanced Apprenticeship

Mechanical Design Engineering

Skills

Languages: Javascript/Typescript, Python, HTML/CSS

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Next.js, Astro, Node.js, MongoDB (Mongoose), Express.js, PostgreSQL (Drizzle), Redis, Sainty, Tailwind, SCSS, Bootstrap

Tooling: Git, Github, VS Code, Google (Gemini, OAuth2.0), Vercel, Stripe

Soft Skills: Critical thinker, Problem solving, Self-managing, Self-motivating, Management, Hunger for learning